DARRYL CARDEN

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATION AND CUSTOMER SUPPORT

(303) 253 2220 - darrylcarden@comcast.net

IT systems and customer support professional with 14+ years experience delivering end user support and systems troubleshooting for computer and network systems in companies ranging from small under 20 user businesses to large, global corporations. Experienced in designing, building, configuring, and supporting information systems from tablets and desktops to large scale remote hosted virtualized deployments encompassing all data systems for 1000+ user environments.

EXPERIENCE

MANAGED SERVICES ADMIN: 3T Systems (Denver, CO), 2007 – 2014

Work directly with clients as a systems administrator for a managed services hosting provider to plan, design, implement, maintain, and troubleshoot clients information technology systems in a managed data center. Supported products include Windows Server and Desktop operating systems, Linux servers, DNS (Bind and MS), DHCP, Active Directory, Exchange, database servers (SQL, MySQL), Virtualization, Citrix, Apache and IIS web servers, and basic networking and routing.

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR: EDS Corp/Maxtor (Longmont, CO), 2000 – 2007

Monitor and support broad range of mission-critical servers within enterprise-class data center, including Windows and Linux operating systems, web servers, Vignette Content Management/Application Portal platforms, and Microsoft server platform software. Primary focus on supporting all hosting platforms and assisting web design team for all maxtor.com web sites in addition to providing general data center and end user support as needed. Also studied for and received VMWare VCP certification.

ASSISTANT PARTS MANAGER: Empire Nissan (Lakewood, CO), 1991 – 2000

EDUCATION

BACHELORS PROGRAM FOR COMPUTER NETWORK MANAGEMENT: Westwood College Of Technology (Westminster, CO)

Completed all associate-level courses

W.J. PALMER HIGH SCHOOL: Colorado Springs, CO, 1987

PROJECTS

ADDITIONAL TRAINING: Studied using various online courses from 2015-current in aerial photography, video, as well as video editing using Adobe Premier Pro and other editing software. Demo video available here: https://vimeo.com/354796347

Studied for and received FAA part 107 certification for piloting of small unmanned aircraft. Certificate number 4247918 issued 13 April 2019 valid until April 2022

DESERT SKY UNMANNED AERIAL SERVICES: 2019-2020

Attempted to start an unmanned aerial services provider to provide drone services primarily focusing on aerial mapping using WebODM open source software to do orthomosaic mapping for construction and other projects.